Hello friends, today we will discuss a question that is on the
mind of every hair transplant patient: is
hair
transplant a safe procedure? Safety in
Hair
Transplant? Hair transplant is a
superficial surgical procedure that is
very safe. We perform hair transplant under local
anesthesia. Can there be any
side effects? Yes, local
anesthesia can sometimes cause allergic reactions. However, as a
precaution,
we
administer a test dose before the hair transplant. If the patient experiences any
reactions, we become aware of them in advance,
which we manage. We
proceed only if there is no reaction to the hair transplant. Performing
surgery under local anesthesia does
not result in the side effects of general anesthesia. The
patient remains conscious throughout the surgery,
can see and hear. Can there be
any infection due to this safety?
Yes, there can be
infections, but if
we perform it properly under OT conditions, there are chances of
infection.  The chances also become very minimal
like the precautions we take, we do
proper OT fumigation, take
care of the medications, take care of the monitoring of the patient, due to
which these side effects are
not seen. Can there be
pain during hair transplant? Yes,
during hair transplant, when we
give local anesthesia to the patient, the patient may feel pain for two-three
minutes till the effect of anesthesia comes,
but to
reduce that also we take proper precautions, due to which the
pain also reduces. Is there
pain in the post surgical hair transplant area? After any surgery or
any injury, there may be some pain,
for which proper medications are given, due to which the
patient feels almost no pain, but some patients have this
pain, for which medicines are given. Can there be
swelling on the face after hair transplant? Yes,
some people get swelling on the face after hair transplant, to
remove this, some precautions are taken,
which we apply on the head of the patient.  A crepe
bandage, i.e. a close bandage, is tied like a tight bandage.
Some medication is
given which reduces the swelling and to
prevent infection, some
antibiotics and some medications are given. So,
in terms of safety, hair
transplant is a very safe procedure. It is
very important where and how to do it. If
you get it done by a proper doctor
in proper OT conditions, then it is a very
safe and simple procedure. It is a superficial
surgical procedure which is a very safe
procedure. If you do it in a proper place
with proper precautions, then you do
not face any problem. When it comes to safety,
because this is a local anesthesia procedure,
we do
not see the side effects of general anesthesia in this.
Very little local anesthesia is
given due to which only some part of your head from
where hair is removed or
transplanted is affected, that is zero.
Apart from this, as a precaution, we
also give a test dose of local anesthesia first. The
patient should not be given any medicine from this.  Is there any
allergy because
generally the side effects that are seen are seen
related to allergy, so if we
give a test dose of it beforehand and when we
see that the patient is not getting any side effects, only then
we start the hair transplant
surgery, the second most important
precaution is that you should do it
in proper OT conditions, you must have
heard or read some things that
these side effects happened after hair transplant, you must have
also heard the news of someone's death, that was
because they did not take proper precautions, it was done
in a room in a beauty parlor, which is done
in proper OT saline, so
all these side effects are also not seen,
some other side effects which are normal side
effects after hair transplant
like swelling on the head, some people get it
because it goes away in four to five days, for
which some medication is given, thank you